在平板的结构里，当列表项被点击的时候
In the tablet wire frames,
when a list item is selected,
被激活的状态显示了蓝色背景
it shows this blue
activated state background.
这可以通过设置列表项的背景为一个
This can be done by setting
the background of the list item to be
state drawable来完成
a state drawable.
我们可以看一下StateListDrawable的文档
We can look at the documentation for
连接在下面
this StateListDrawable,
which is linked below.
事实上，StateListDrawable允许你根据视图不同的状态(State)
Essentially, a StateListDrawable allows
you to specify different drawables
来指定不同的drawable
based on the state of the view.
我们提供了一些StateListDrawable的代码
We provide you a code for
the StateListDrawable.
在 res 目录下新建一个drawable文件夹，把代码拖进去
Drop it in by creating a drawable
folder under the res directory.
当设置为列表项的背景时，我们看到背景默认是透明的
When set as the background of a list
item, we see that the background is just
就像这里的today_layout
transparent by default such
as this today lay out here.
当视图被按下，我们看到一个灰色的背景
When the view is pressed,
then we see a grey background.
当视图被激活，我们看到的是蓝色
When the view is activated,
then we see this blue color.
这也意味着被选中的列表项在两个窗格模式下
This is also indicating that it's
the selected item in the two pane mode.
对于5.0及以上的api我们还有第二个
We also have a second version
of the touch_selector file for
版本的touch_selector文件
Lollipop devices and above.
它保存在drawable-v21文件夹下
This is saved in
the drawable-v21 folder.
把api设置为21及以上
Set on platforms API level 21 and
它将使用这个版本的touch_selector
above, it will use this
version of the touch_selector.
在旧设备上，它会向下兼容的使用
On older devices it will fall back
to the touch_selector in the base
基本drawable文件夹
drawable folder.
material design 的一个主要原则就是易响应的交互
One of the main principles of material
design is responsive interaction.
实现它的一个途径就是当用户触摸了设备的时候
One way to accomplish this is that
when a user touches a device,
设备可以响应这个交互
the device will acknowledge
the interaction, and
一个波纹从触摸点开始向外扩散
a ripple will radiate out
from the touch point.
ripple drawable 可以做到这些
This is done with a ripple drawable.
你要在drawable 的xml文件里添加ripple元素
You can add a ripple element in
your state list drawable xml.
对于v21的touch selector，除了按下的状态，其余都是一样的
For the v21 touch selector, it's the
same except that for the pressed state,
我们有一个灰色触摸回馈的ripple drawable
we have a ripple drawable with
a grey color for touch feedback.
在5.0设备上，你会看到波纹
And on a Lollypop device,
you can see the ripple.
在list item layout里，我们设置背景为这个touch_selector
In the list item layout, we set the
background to be this touch_selector.
同样也为list_item_forecast_today布局设置好
We do the same for
the list_item_forecast_today layout.
回到touch_selector文件中，我希望在这标记一些颜色
Back in the touch_selector file, I want
to note that there's some colors here.
@android color 是系统框架定义好的颜色
The @android color notation is for
a framework defined color.
其它的颜色是我们定义在 colors.xml文件里的
The other colors are ones that we
defined in the colors.xml file.
这个文件在应用里的Values文件夹下
This file is located in
the Values folder of your app.
在重要的位置存储一些颜色值是必要的
It's useful to store colors
in a central location
特别是你需要在应用里多次引用它的时候
if you need a reference colors
multiple times in your app.
As a hint.
为了使列表项显示被激活的状态，你可以看一下
to make a list item show its activated
state, you can look at the documentation
listView的属性里的choiceMode的文档
for the XML attribute choiceMode for
the ListView.
当你找到正确的属性，你就会意识到你对于不同的窗格模式，
Once you find the right attribute,
you'll realize that you want different
需要不一样的行为
behavior for
one pane versus two pane mode.
你可以在java代码里更改这些行为
While you could change the behaviour
programatically in the Java code,
我们更倾向于你只使用xml资源的style来实现它
we'd like you to do it purely via
the resource XML files using a style.
读一下这个文档，看看你可以定义哪些style
Read this doc to learn about how
styles can be defined in XML.
以及使用你之前学过的哪些方法
And use what you learned earlier about
defining alternative resources for
为不用尺寸的设备定义可选资源
different size devices.
总的来说，style是一种你可以把视图的属性集合在一起的
In general, styles are a way that
you can group together attributes
方式
for a view.
比如，这些text的属性被style的codeFont替换掉了
For example, these text attributes
are replaced by this style CodeFont.
CodeFont是定义在styles.xml文件里的style
The CodeFont style is defined
in the styles.xml file
它在Vaules文件夹下
located in the Values folder.
你也能让style继承其它的style,只要指定一个父style就可以
You can also have styles inherit other
styles by specifying the parent.
你可以查看这个页面上其它的例子
There are a couple of other examples
you can check out on this page.
这才是当你完成这个app时它应有的样子
This is what the app should
look like when you're done.
在单窗格模式里，我们看不到激活的状态
In one pane mode,
we don't see the activated state.
但是仍然有规则的按下状态，
But there's still the regular
press state with the ripple and
波纹扩散然后消失
then it goes away